Michael Tackett

331-300-4414 | michaelt@michaelt.dev | Aurora, Aurora, Illinois

Professional Summary

Multifaceted, junior full stack web developer with a track record of agile development and successful collaboration across multiple industries. Utilizing both business and developer experience to deliver consistent results that exceed client needs and expectations.

Skills

JavaScript, CSS, HTML, React, PHP, JSON, MySQL, Express.js, Node.js, APIs, MongoDB, GitHub, Web Design, Responsive Web Design, SEO, SEO Tools, Client Relations, Business Management, Critical Thinking, WordPress, Agile Development, SCSS, Figma

Education

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities Campus | Minnesota Certification, Full Stack Web Development | 03/2022

Work Experience

Armortechs | DeKalb, Illinois

Web Developer / SEO Specialist | 11/2021 - 09/2022

- Implemented SEO process changes that both increased SEO efficiency by 30% and lead to a universal traffic increase for all clients
- · Redesigned the website of a law firm's that resulted in a 15% increase in booked consultations
- Built WordPress websites based on design templates
- Maintained WordPress websites: updated plug-ins, performed back-ups, updated client websites, etc.
- Developed custom WordPress plug-ins
- Conducted keyword research on a plethora of industries
- Produced competitive analysis reports and SEO audits
- · Created campaigns targeting high-value keywords

DHL | Aurora, Illinois

Forklift Operator | 01/2020 - 11/2021

- Operated stand-up forklift
- · Maintained forklift certification
- · Abided by all forklift safety rules and regulations

Mobil Gas Station | North Aurora, Illinois

Assistant Manager | 03/2017 - 01/2020

- Increased sales by 12% via various in-store campaigns and promotions
- Redesigned store layout resulting in a yearly increase of guests by 7%
- Ensured guest concerns were resolved in a swift manner with professionalism and emphasis on guest satisfaction
- Assisted with scheduling and payroll
- · Ran reports on fuel tank system
- Scheduled maintenance for both fuel pumps and store supply tanks
- · Received, stocked, and rotated merchandise
- · Supply ordering/inventory
- · Built new store displays
- Maintained store cleanliness

M.E. Computer Systems | Aurora, Illinois EHR Specialist | 10/2011 - 02/2017

- · Train doctors and their staff on EHR software
- Assist clients in software setup
- Create software-based, educational content highlighting key features and functions

- Maintain familiarity of ICD-10 codes and medical terminologyBuild and evolve rapport with doctors, hospitals, and industry leaders

Languages

English